W. Eben Burr Oral History Project Ms B112
Archivists' Toolkit
W. Eben Burr Oral History Project
1958-2005
Ms B112
Archivists' Toolkit
5.5 Linear feet (11 boxes, 71 tapes)
This collection contains taped interviews with residents of Fairfield, CT spanning 1958-2005.
various
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
This collection was donated by Eben Burr.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of 71 taped interviews with Fairfield residents from 1958-2005. The interviewees discuss their family background as well as their childhood memories of Fairfield. Also discussed are occupations, membership in clubs (Grange, Boy Scouts, Fairfield Sportsman and the Southport Garden Club),and leisure activities.
Other key topics consist of stories related to the section of town in which the interviewees lived (Southport, the Beach area, Mill Plain, Samp Mortar, Black Rock, Grasmere, Barlow Plain, Sasco Hill, Post Road, Stratfield, the Fairfield University area and Greenfield Hill) as well as personal or family experiences there.
Some subjects explored more in depth include real estate and development (Nicholas Fingelly) and small business (Angelina Mercurio, co-owner of Mercurio's Grocery). Other major topics: boating and sailing, banking and finance, farming and gardening, the Fire and Police departments, historical sites, manufacturing, medicine, politics and town government, religion and churches, and Fairfield public and private education.
Each tape has a signed release form and a transcript for each interview through tape number 45. The finding aid is arranged alphabetically by last name.
Burr, William E. (William Eben), 1901-1996; Fairfield (Conn.)--History; Oral history--United States.
- Agonis, Edward, 2/3/1994; Tape 43
- Banks, W. Elmore, 4/1/1990; Tape 14
- Banks, Elizabeth, n.d.; Tape 79
- Barate, John, 9/10/1997; Tape 57
- Barrett, Roswell, 4/25/1990; Tape 27
- Beach, William, 7/30/1991; Tape 39
- Berthelson, Bob, n.d.; Tape 56
- Bullard, Florence (Mrs. Harold), 4/29/1960; Tape 11
- Burr, Eben, 3/5/1991; Tape 22
- Burr, Lottie, 4/19/1958; Tape 13
- Burr, Howard, 9/26/1990; Tape 38
- Butkus, Anna, n.d.; Tape 68
- Caco, Sophia Zachreski, n.d.; Tape 59
- Cahill, Robert, n.d.; Tape 81
- Carroll, Patrick, 1/16/1990; Tape 28
- Clark, Cameron, 7/3/1997; Tape 54
- Croford (Crofutt), Frank, n.d.; Tape 34
- Daly, Michael, n.d.; Tape 66
- Daniels, Frank (town engineer), n.d.; Tape 60
- Decker, Margaret, 5/27/1997; Tape 51
- Durrell, Jacquelyn, 12/11/1997; Tape 65
- Fanton, John, 4/11/1954; Tape 12
- Figlar, Helen, 4/20/2005; Tape unknown
- Fingelly, Nicholas H., 2/10/1990; Tape 5
- Ford, John, n.d.; Tape 74
- Fraezak, Bruce, n.d.; Tape 73
- Friedman, Muriel Smirnoff, 7/3/1991; Tape 7
- Gardner, Mildred, n.d.; Tape 47
- Glover, Sam, n.d.; Tape 45
- Hansson, Frances Mason, 5/12/1990; Tape 18
- Hayes, Virginia, 1/14/1996, 4/1/1997; Tapes 49 and 50
- Healy, Eugene, 4/11/1991; Tape 32
- Hertzel, John, 4/9/1990; Tape 17
- Holman, Leroy, n.d.; Tape 41
- Hull, Fred, 5/1/1991; Tape 30
- Instone, Bertha, n.d.; Tape 52
- Jackson, Theodosia Hawley, n.d.; Tape 80
- Kinsman, Russ, 6/13/1990; Tape 19
- Kish, Dorothy, 11/13/1997; Tape 70
- Kish, George, 9/15/1989; Tape 8
- Kranyik, Margaret, 11/8/1990; Tape 25
- Krewson, Helen Mary, 10/23/1990; Tape 26
- Kunin, Leonard, n.d.; Tape 76
- Lindsay, Charles, 10/11/1993; Tape 42
- Lobdell, Eleann, 7/14/2003; Tape 86
- Longstreth, Alice, 4/5/1987; Tape 58
- MacKenzie, Roderick, n.d.; Tape 83
- MacKenzie, Laura B., n.d.; Tape 84
- Mercurio, Angelina, 3/21/1990; Tape 1
- Merwin, Rodney, 5/1/1991; Tape 31
- Morgan, Pat, n.d.; Tape 63
- Neale, Edward H., 4/11/1991; Tape 33
- Papageorge, Angelus, n.d.; Tape 62
- Park, Janice, 6/1/1991; Tape 35
- Parsons, Mattie Etta Rand, 2/27/1990; Tape 7
- Pekar, John, 1/22/1999; Tape 72
- Penczer, Rudolph, 4/5/1990; Tape 29
- Perry, Fred, 4/13/1958; Tape 9
- Perry, Eliza, 7/31/1991; Tape 36
- Police, Fairfield, n.d.; Tape 82
- Politi, Raymond, Tape 77
- Quinn, Carol A., Tape 78
- Reed, Marion, 8/7/1990; Tapes 20 and 21
- Reeves, Libby, n.d.; Tape 55
- Roche, Louis Curtis, 3/15/1990; Tape 3
- Selleck, Arthur, 10/28/1990; Tape 24
- Sherwood, Mr. and Mrs. Harold, 3/13/1958; Tape 10
- Skog, Nils, 12/2/1992; Tape 71
- Smith, Vita Seward, n.d.; Tape 75
- Smith, Pat, n.d.; Tape 61
- Sturges, John A., 1/18/1990; Tape 6
- Sullivan, John, 11/16/1998; Tape 40
- Sutherland, John, Tape 85
- Szepessy, Jack, 1/25/1994; Tape unknown
- Szepessy, John, 10/26/1993; Tape 44
- Treadwell, Nelis, 11/28/1990; Tape 23
- Trotter, Elizabeth, 1/29/1990; Tape 4
- Tucker, Ike (Irwin), 7/8/1997; Tape 53
- Wakeman, Joseph, 3/25/1990; Tape 16
- Walsh, Charles, 2/6/1990; Tape 2
- Wilbur, Elinor, 5/25/1999; Tape 69
- Yaw, Frank, 1/28/1997; Tape 67